# Frederik Ring

Software Engineer

+49 179 5421146 frederik.ring@posteo.de

#### **SUMMARY**

With over ten years of experience ranging from frontend development to backend work and maintaining and scaling infrastructure, I like to focus on delivering maintainable solutions, solving and automating away what is brittle and prevents teams from creating robust software.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Software Engineer - Wikimedia

Jan 2023 → Current (5 month)

I work on infrastructure topics for Wikibase and Wikibase Cloud, a SaaS offering that allows users to run their own Wikibase instances.

#### Senior Software Engineer - Field Intelligence

Oct 2018 → Dec 2022 (4 years, 2 months)

I managed the infrastructure and contributed to platform development for an offline-first application used for supply chain management for medical goods in rural Africa.

### Web Developer - Ecosia

Nov 2016  $\rightarrow$  May 2018 (1 year, 7 months)

I worked on all parts of the stack of an eco-centric search engine built around the Bing API.

# Lead Frontend Developer - tracdelight

Jan 2015 → Oct 2016 (1 year, 10 months)

I led the frontend team in developing a modern replacement for an existing legacy system.

#### Frontend Developer - ShopLove

Oct 2013  $\rightarrow$  Dec 2014 (1 year, 3 months)

I contributed to the frontend of a monolithic asp.net application.

# Lead Developer - METERMADE

Jan 2013 → Mar 2014 (1 year, 2 months)

I developed and designed a web shop for customizable furniture.

#### **SKILLS**

I like to work with and am proficient in: JavaScript, Go, Python, Linux, Docker, Bash

#### **ON THE WEB**

- → https://www.frederikring.com
- → https://github.com/m90
- → https://blog.frederikring.com

#### **LANGUAGES**

- → German (native)
- → English (fluent)
- → French (advanced)

## Interactive Developer and Animator - freelance

 $2006 \rightarrow \text{Sep } 2013 \text{ (7 years, 9 months)}$ 

I contributed both code and animation to various projects in the domain of children's TV and education.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Diploma in Animation - Filmakademie Baden-Württemberg

2001 → 2006

I studied classical and digital animation, focusing on 2D animation.

#### **OPEN SOURCE**

#### Offen - Co-Author

https://github.com/offen/offen

Offen is a fair and open web analytics software. Funded by the NGI initiative / NLNet.

### docker-volume-backup - Author

https://github.com/offen/docker-volume-backup A Docker image for backing up data.

# mochify.js - Maintainer

https://github.com/mantoni/mochify.js

Mochify lets you run unit tests in headless browsers.

#### **WRITING**

# Privacy focus? Consider the cookie - Blog Post (2021)

https://www.offen.dev/blog/privacy-cookies/

A look at how to use cookies in a user- and privacy-friendly way.

#### Untold Roads to v1.0 - Blog Post (2020)

https://www.offen.dev/blog/untold-roads-versioning-early-stage-software/ Thoughts on how to version early stage software.

# Testing and testable JavaScript for absolute beginners and occasional programmers - Blog Post (2018)

https://blog.frederikring.com/articles/javascript-testing-for-beginners/

A gentle introduction to software testing for self taught programmers like myself.

# What I learned building an api.ai webhook - *Blog Post* (2017)

https://blog.frederikring.com/articles/building-an-api-webhook/

Collecting things I wished I knew before embarking on a hobby project using conversational AI.

#### **TALKS**

# Let's end this arms race - with Hendrik Niefeld (2021/2022)

Privacy Week Vienna 2021, FOSDEM 2022, COSCUP 2022 et al.

What would privacy on the web look like if we'd start cooperating?